(A Reassuring Start)
It's good to see you!
- Good to see you. - Hello.
The Year of the Blue Snake, 2025 has dawned.
- Happy New Year. - Happy New Year.
Happy New Year.
To welcome the New Year, I prepared a gift for the members...
as someone who was born...
- in the Year of the Snake. - It's a New Year's money gift!
- You didn't have to prepare them. - Do a deep bow before saying that!
- Let's give him a deep bow. - Don't.
- No. - It's about time we did one.
- I can only wire you. Sit down. - Really? That's good enough for me.
- Give me your watch, at least. - I don't have one.
- "Give me your watch, at least." - He's not wearing one today.
Ta-da.
I brought this so I could feed you something delicious.
- Ta-da. - Goodness.
- What is it? Is it rice cake? - Yes, it's rice cake.
I was hoping we'd have a good start after sharing rice cake.
- That's why I got rice cake. - Goodness.
- All right. Line up. - Goodness.
- Here you go. - It's really fascinating.
Gosh, the scent is amazing.
The scent is crazy good.
Thank you for this, Hyun Moo.
- It's really soft. Right? - Yes.
- It's good. - It's good.
It has a rich taste of black sesame, right?
It's really delicious.
(A filling beginning of the New Year)
Let's start off in a good light.
Let's check out KEY's day, which he spent meaningfully.
(A Shining Graduation Certificate)
A Shining Graduation Certificate?
(Clothes scattered on the floor)
(Left open)
(Squirming under a flower blanket)
- Wait. This isn't his house. - A flower blanket?
- What is this? - Where is that?
Where is he?
It's my parent's place.
- Oh, your parents' place? - In Daegu?
Yes, my parents' place in Daegu.
I slept over at my parents' place in Daegu after a long time.
Your mom must've loved it.
- Goodness. - She did.
- That's right. - Today is...
a really big day for our family.
It's the last day of work for my mother, Ms. Kim Sun Hee.
(The last day of work)
(KEY prepared a trip for his mother last time.)
- Oh, right. They went to Japan. - That's right.
(A gift his mother loved)
(A sweet mother-son trip that made everyone envious)
(She worked as a head nurse in 2022.)
(Then she got promoted to a chief.)
That's right! You celebrated her promotion...
- in Japan. - That's right.
It's already been years.
She said she was going to go to work like usual...
- and pack her stuff afterward. - Really?
I went with her to celebrate it...
and to make it a lasting memory for her.
I'm spending the whole day for my mother...
and to throw a surprise party for my mother's retirement.
I'm going to spend it well.
The last day of her work.
How must the last day of work feel?
- She worked there for so long. - She worked there her whole life.
- She did. - She worked there...
- That's right. - for more than 30 years.
- Yes, for 36 years. - That's really amazing.
It couldn't have hit her...
- on the day. - Right.
It must've felt odd.
(He's still lazing around in bed.)
I need to go now.
It's your mother's last day of work, so why are you still in bed?
What...
Why are you suddenly mad?
- What made him mad? - It's still early.
- Your mother is working hard, - But...
- and it's her last day. - I mean...
I'm suddenly mad.
Why are you so mad?
- I went there to celebrate. - Exactly.
(Get up now.)
No.
(I can't be in bed.)
(He hurriedly leaves the bedroom.)
How do I turn the lights on again?
Gosh, it's so bright.
(KEY enters the kitchen as soon as he gets up.)
(Let's see.)
(Opening)
(Closing)
(He rummages through everywhere and checks their stuff.)
(Rattling)
With this...
(He takes out a pot.)
Will this be big enough?
(Let's use a bigger pot.)
- He must be cooking something. - A lunch box?
You said...
- your mom was a bad cook. - Yes.
(Is he cooking for his mother?)
(Grabbing something from the utility room.)
What's that?
(This time, he opens their fridge.)
Now you're a certified Craftsman Cook in Western food.
- Are you making an omelet? - No. There's no way.
(The dish he's best at after omelet)
(All right.)
(He moves something heavy.)
- Is it octopus? - I couldn't make her...
- Is it oyster? - an ordinary dish.
What is it? It must be something in season.
I'm curious.
(Pouring)
- It must be clams. - It sounds like clams.
- I know. - Or abalones?
- Oysters? They're crabs? - They're crabs.
I think I've mentioned this while talking with the members.
My grandma used to make this really often when I was young.
It's braised crab in soy sauce.
(KEY was reminded of something upon seeing Na Rae's kimchi.)
(It's been over 10 years since Grandma passed.)
(He really craved her braised crab in soy sauce.)
(He spent the whole day finding the right taste.)
(Using the seed soy sauce that's been boiled as a base)
(He found the correct recipe after twists and turns.)
- That's right. - I thought...
everyone in the country ate it.
It was introduced, but no one knew.
You'd never heard of it, right?
- I hadn't. - No.
- There's such food. - Yes, there's such food.
- I've never heard of braised crab. - Right.
I thought my mom and dad would really love it...
if I made it for them.
After eating it together, I went to school, and Mom went to work.
We have memories of that.
I thought she'd be reminded of the old days...
if I made her Grandma's food.
(KEY prepares braised crab in soy sauce.)
(Opening)
Gosh, they're still alive!
(Surprised by the squirming live crabs)
They're live blue crabs.
(Fresh)
- Gosh, they're plump. - It's not easy.
Of course not.
(Clenching his teeth)
That's it. You're doing well.
Let's leave this unconscious.
Must you use live blue crabs...
- for that dish? - Yes, you must.
You must use live blue crabs.
(The next step is important.)
I brought the seed soy sauce from home.
(Pouring the seed soy sauce he brought from home)
It's the same seed soy sauce I used to make the same dish.
So it was used to braise crabs.
- You stored it? - I stored it.
- That's amazing. - You pour it...
when you make a new batch. Then you store the sauce again...
to make another batch.
You must pack that first when you move.
Of course. Seed soy sauce...
- is really important. - He must pack it first.
- There... - It'll be with him forever.
There used to be a seed soy sauce thief in old restaurants.
- Of course. - But it'll be gone once you eat it.
- You don't throw the old one. - You boil it again.
You keep boiling it for decades.
- I see. - The taste changes completely.
- You can't even buy it. - You have a seed lunchbox.
- Seed soy sauce... - A seed lunchbox?
(The expert in seed fried rice, Seed84)
(Seed fried rice is my secret technique.)
(He seasons it in earnest.)
Adding minced garlic.
You're adding more soy sauce?
- We can't even copy it... - That's the secret...
- because we don't have the seed. - of making the sauce.
You can use this recipe when you first make the sauce.
With 1.5 portions of water, add 1 portion of starch syrup.
With a ratio like that, add 0.2 portions of plum extract.
And 0.2 portions of fish sauce.
- Oh, you must add vinegar too. - Oh, you add sand eel sauce.
- That must be good. - That must be good.
- Add lots of chili powder. - Chili powder.
(Then add a few rounds of savory sesame oil.)
- It needs sesame oil too. - That's unique.
But that's... It looks delicious.
It must be delicious to braise tofu with it.
You must add a lot of water to keep the crabs completely soaked.
- You add potato too? - Yes.
- That's really unique. - Is it a Daegu dish?
No, there's no such dish.
(Braised crab in soy sauce that only KEY's family enjoys)
(In the soy sauce with various condiments...)
Bye.
So you boil it down like that.
- That's really unique. - What is...
(Adding blue crabs one by one)
- I wonder how it tastes. - I'm really curious too.
(Adding lots of onions that have been cut)
(Adding potatoes on top)
(Adding his love too)
That's it.
Ring the alarm in ten minutes.
- That's it? - Yes. I just need to boil it.
- That's really simple. - It is.
- Boil it for exactly ten minutes? - Yes.
(Exhaling)
Gosh, there's a lot to do.
Goodness.
- You're throwing a party at home? - Yes.
- We're having it at home. - Your mother would love it.
I got tape too.
I got lots of stuff.
(Opening gently)
(Grabbing)
(Mother I'm proud of)
- Gosh. - He's such a good son.
He's a really good son.
I've never done that for my parents.
- No. - She would love it.
My mother loves cute things like that.
That's why I wanted to make a figure for her.
- It's like a trophy. - That'd be lovely.
He's such a good son.
(Mother I'm proud of, Kim Sun Hee)
(The good son, KEY, begins decorating the house.)
(Determined)
(Let's speed it up.)
(His eyes and hands are busy moving.)
Oh, he's blowing balloons one by one.
That's a lot of work.
(He makes a balloon bouquet without moving or resting.)
(Ringing)
You should turn it off.
Okay, I'm coming.
(Hurrying)
(One is done.)
(A silver curtain to add to the party vibe)
(Covered in sweat)
- He sweats a lot. - That's right.
- My parents' house... - It's hot.
is really hot as though it's heated with ondol.
- It's boiling hot. - You know what I mean, right?
They increase the temperature even more when I'm coming.
They wanted their son to stay warm.
(Working hard to pay back his mom's warm love)
(Pressing hard to fix it so it wouldn't fall)
(Hanging a banner)
That's nice.
Nice!
- You need a banner like that. - Yes, it's a must.
It's a must. My mom keeps all those.
Right. She seemed to like it.
- Your mother would love it. - You can't leave it out.
(We root for the 2nd chapter of your shining life.)
(Adding more decorations on top of the banner)
That's nice.
The hearts are cute.
How can you not feel embarrassed and do such things well?
I can always do it.
It's all set.
(We root for the 2nd chapter of your shining life.)
That's so cute.
(Bringing the balloon bouquets he made in advance)
(Placing the appreciation plaque and her figure)
It's pretty.
(Great. This is perfect.)
(Sighing)
Gosh, it's so hectic.
- It's so hectic. - It looks exhausting already.
(He got changed in no time.)
(He's leaving the house in the midst of party preparation?)
Where is he going?
Taxi?
- Hello. - Hello.
(Curious)
(Entering somewhere)
Thank you.
Goodness.
Where is that?
The place I went to is where my mother worked for 36 years.
It's Kyungpook National University Hospital.
Gosh, for 36 years?
The hospital is huge.
My mother...
gave birth in her first workplace.
She also got surgery there when she was ill.
Every moment of her life is in those 36 years.
The first and last.
That's how it was like for old people.
- They'd work for just one place. - That's right.
That's amazing.
(KEY got out in front of the hospital.)
- Hey, Ki Bum. - Mom, I'm here.
- Yes. - Where should I go to?
There's Building One on the rightmost side.
- The Cancer Center? - Yes. Come to the second floor.
The second floor? Okay.
- All right. - Okay.
She used to work in the main building when I was young,
so I'm really familiar with it.
But she moved to that building after I grew up.
Kyungpook National University Hospital...
is my mom's first and last workplace.
She worked there as a nurse.
(After the years where there were 3 shifts...)
My gosh. That's the old nurse uniform.
- It's really long ago. - Oh, my.
She used to work for the auditing department...
and was a head nurse.
Now, she's the chief nurse.
(She received a commendation from the Ministry of Health and Welfare.)
A commendation?
I'd always tag along with my dad...
on her way to work. We'd also wait for her when she was done with work.
I have so many memories like those.
And I really loved that time.
I thought it'd be meaningful to be with her...
on her last day of work.
I strongly wanted to be there for her.
I wanted to be with her when she was done with work...
rather than when she was going to work.
- That'd feel more empty. - Right. That's more appropriate.
Hyun Moo, you're planning to become a good son in five years.
I'm not even sure when their last day of work was.
- We were each... - What about when they got off work?
Get off work? I didn't even know where they worked.
- So... - We fended for ourselves.
- Wait. - You're such a good son.
You must know...
- that this year is the last year. - What a good son.
- Okay. - This year is the last one.
- A year is quite long. - It's the last year.
My mother worked her whole life...
at an affiliated kindergarten.
I never got to do something like that for her.
Be honest. You didn't know when her last day was, right?
I mean, I noticed...
- she had retired already one day. - One day?
- You and I are the same. - What are you saying?
"Mom, aren't you going to work?"
(Sorry. I realized it too late, Mom.)
(Let's be a good son from now.)
(Walking over to be with his mom on her last day of work)
(Daegu, North Gyeongsang Area Cancer Center)
Gosh, it's huge.
It really is huge.
Here it is.
(Cancer Management Department, Reception)
- Hello. - You're here.
- Hello. - Hi!
- Mom! - Yes.
(They're glad to see each other.)
Gosh, Mother.
I mean...
- What's all this? - Hello.
- What's this? - I brought it for the team.
- Really? - Her pitch is higher.
- Gosh, put it up here. - Right.
- Goodness. Say hello to them. - Goodness.
- They're my colleagues. - Hello.
They're so excited.
Hello. Is that your seat?
Yes, this is my seat.
You're all working so hard.
This is my seat.
There's nothing much to pack.
Isn't the seat where you can see the whole room...
for someone in the highest position?
- That's right. - That's right. On the inside.
I saw Mom's seat as soon as I opened the door.
I realized that my mom made it to a high position.
I could see how she made it...
to the final position of her career.
She wasn't in such a position...
- when I first went there. - That's right.
I always visited my mom's office once or twice a year.
Since I was young.
Her senior colleagues would tell me that she's working hard.
We used to use landline, so I'd call and ask for my mom.
- That's how we used to call. - That's right.
The one who picked up the phone would compliment my mom in person.
They'd greet me happily.
That's the culture we had when I was young.
Let's go. We'll be in the meeting room.
- Goodness. - It must be heavy.
(Heading to the meeting room, following his mom's lead)
Ta-da.
You brought me here to show this to me, right?
(A banner to celebrate her retirement)
She must be popular among her colleagues.
Yes, she is.
(We root for the new beginning of Ms. Kim Sun Hee.)
What's with this photo edit?
It's your life-size cutout.
- Does it actually exist? - It's you?
- You're there too? - Yes.
- What is this? - Oh, my.
- That's so witty of them. - It was my birthday.
- My colleagues... - Oh, it was your birthday.
threw me a party.
How should I give these out?
(By the way, how should I give these out?)
Why did you bring so much?
What is it?
- You signed all of them? - Gosh.
(Surprised)
Oh, my.
(A bag of gifts he prepared for his mom's colleagues)
Oh, my gosh.
(There's more gift?)
(Exclaiming)
Isn't it so moving?
What is it?
What is this?
(The second gift is a ballpoint pen.)
Nurses use ballpoint pens a lot.
No matter how digitalized it has become,
they use ballpoint pens a lot.
So I prepared pens with a message engraved.
Oh, they're for her colleagues?
- Yes. - My, how considerate of you.
"Please brag to others that I gave this to you."
I carved in a message to thank them.
- My name should be included... - He's so considerate.
for them to brag.
That's right.
- You should show it. - Of course.
What is this?
You carved it on all of them?
Of course.
You did well.
Gosh, it's rewarding to have a son.
(Feeling proud)
How should I hand them out?
Guys, you should...
Come on in.
(Surprised)
(Her colleagues are gathered in front of the door.)
- He brought these for us. - I wanted to give them out.
He's our center head.
- Oh, you're the center head. Hello. - Can I shake his hand?
It's nice to meet you.
He's the head of the cancer center.
- Oh, my. - It's my album.
(Giving a gift to him right away)
By the way, sir...
- There's something he must get. - there's something I must get.
- What is it? - My daughter...
Oh, she bought it.
- Sign it here. - I should sign it?
She told me to get your autograph. Then she'd study hard.
(Signing his autograph without holding back)
He's done it a lot.
- Your mother must be so proud. - Thank you.
She even bought the album?
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- Be healthy. - Thank you for everything.
- Here. Please take them. - My son signed all of them.
- Really? Thank you. - I already signed them.
It's nice to have a successful son.
- He's her pride. - I'm even more thankful.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- You're all working so hard. - Thank you.
- Sure. - You really made her proud.
- I rarely have a chance like that. - Thank you for your hard work.
(Smiling broadly thanks to her son)
- Let's take a photo to wrap up. - Now...
That's right.
Should we take a photo with the white backdrop?
Let's take it in front of that.
- This? But it's... - Yes.
Your life-size cutout was always with us,
- but you're here yourself. - Let's take a photo with him.
One, two, three.
(A group photo with KEY in person)
Let's go.
(Grabbing his arm tight)
There was an order of events my mother planned ahead.
(My son feels especially reliable today.)
(His mother enters the room first.)
- Hello. - Hello.
(Where is this?)
- Hello. - Where is that?
- Hello. - Oh, my. It's KEY.
Gosh, department head.
Hello.
It's KEY.
(It's the office of the nurse department head.)
It's the nurse department where my mom used to work.
- It's nice to meet you. - Hello.
He came to see me as it's my last day of work.
- How fascinating. - I'll give you my album.
- I'm enjoying your shows a lot. - Thank you so much.
(Giving her a gift with gratitude)
- Thank you. - Thank you.
They prepared something for you.
- They got it for me last time. - Oh, my.
- Great work. - Thank you.
(They even got her flowers.)
- What are you doing? - I'm so grateful.
You're getting many flowers today.
What are you doing?
How can she be congratulated by so many people?
- It's really not easy. - Wait.
(Then I should give something in return as her son.)
- I'll give these out. - Come.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- Come here, Sung Kyung. - Thank you.
- Here you go. Thank you. - Thank you.
I should've met you in person to congratulate.
It's all right.
- Thank you so much. - Not at all.
Let's grab a meal outside.
Hold on.
(Approaching)
I depended on you a lot.
- I couldn't visit you more. - Of course.
- Goodness. - I feel like crying.
Don't.
- Goodness. - Goodness.
Thank you so much for your hard work.
Gosh, don't cry.
Oh, really?
- You worked so hard. - Right.
I'm grateful.
Thank you for everything.
- Thank you. - I feel the same way.
I never even imagined this...
and didn't expect it at all.
(KEY is standing next to his mom.)
Actually, working with the same people for 20 to 30 years...
and suddenly saying goodbye overnight...
must be a very sad thing for many people.
In some ways, she has spent more time with them...
- than her own family. - Of course.
Seeing her feeling sad and shedding tears...
made me so proud of her.
I came to respect her once more today.
- I'm so glad you went there. - Thank you.
Then, I'll see you all later.
- Okay. - Thank you for everything.
So many people cried because of your retirement.
I heard that so many people cried.
Does it kind of feel like...
when someone is discharged from military service?
- I know, right? - If you act sloppy during service,
- it gets awkward when you leave. - Right.
- That's right. - And nobody cries for you.
- Of course. - That's right.
You say you won't let him slide if you see him outside.
- Right. - Yes.
Wait, Na Rae...
(Wait, Na Rae?)
Na Rae.
- How do you know that? - Of course I know.
- She's a sergeant major. - Yes, the sergeant major knows.
Sergeant Major Park.
It doesn't feel like your retirement party but mine.
Still, it's so nice that my son is here.
- Shall we go over there? - Yes.
- You have a packed schedule. - Yes.
- We had a lot to do. - Right.
- You're making rounds to say bye. - Hello.
Hello.
(They arrive at a conference room?)
Is the mic working?
- A mic? - What is this?
- Please sit here. - Yes, have a seat.
What is it?
- This is too... - We pulled it up a bit.
I think this has gotten too big.
Hello.
Hey, what is this?
- Should we sit here like this? - What is this?
Why is there a photographer here?
- Is the entire staff gathering? - This is the chairwoman.
Oh, hello.
This is the doctor. The professor.
- Thank you for coming. - Thank you.
- Congratulations. - My goodness.
- I should shake hands too. - Yes.
Oh, the hospital director is here.
- All the higher-ups have come. - Thank you.
- Even the director was there. - I've heard so much about you.
This looks like "White Tower."
Was this such an official event?
(Donation Ceremony for Patients in Children's Hospital)
Right, I saw this article.
I wanted to make a meaningful donation...
for my mom's retirement.
But when I got there, they had prepared a ceremony.
(Flustered)
They had opened a donation ceremony.
I was very surprised.
- You should do it, though. - It must be kind of embarrassing.
Gosh, the hospital director... The department head...
My goodness.
- It's like "White Tower." - Oh, my.
- "SHINee, KEY." - "SHINee, KEY."
- We did it like this back then too. - Did we?
- Sure. - "Singer."
- We did it like this back then too. - Look at me.
- I was so embarrassed to sit there. - Sure.
That's the most embarrassing.
- Isn't the view great here? - Sure.
This is the best seat.
Hello, everyone.
We will now begin the donation ceremony...
for patients in the Children's Hospital with SHINee's KEY.
(They begin with refined applause.)
This is so official.
(Shy)
I will now introduce the guests in attendance today.
- There is an order to the event. - You have to do this stuff.
We have the director of...
Kyungpook National University Chilgok Hospital.
Even after all these years, these things stay the same.
The Medical Director of the Children's Hospital is here.
The Chief Secretary is here.
The Director of Nursing is here.
The Pharmacy Manager is here.
- That's it. - You have to mention everyone.
Yes.
SHINee's KEY, Kim Ki Bum is here.
(SHINee's KEY, Kim Ki Bum is here.)
(Dizzy)
Show them your "Lucifer" dance or something.
- Right. - What are you saying?
(Like this)
You should've done something.
You should've gone up to the front and danced.
Next, we will have a congratulatory performance.
(SHINee's KEY, Kim Ki Bum's "Lucifer")
This was more embarrassing than an audition.
Thank you.
(He successfully finishes his solo performance.)
And the mother of SHINee's KEY, Kim Ki Bum,
Head Nurse Kim Sun Hee is here.
(An enthusiastic cheer)
Next, I will announce the donation history of SHINee's KEY.
SHINee's KEY donated 10,000 dollars...
on September 27, 2019.
- My gosh. - You've been donating for a while.
On March 22, 2024,
he donated 864.4 dollars.
When I received awards and stuff, I didn't take it and just donated.
And today, he is donating 50,000 dollars...
- Goodness. Good job. - He is donating 50,000 dollars...
for patients in the Children's Hospital.
- Good job. - Good job.
I'm so proud.
(Proud of him)
We will now sign the donation contract.
Is it usually like this?
- It is. - Yes, you have to do it.
There's a procedure to things.
- You have to take a photo with it. - Of course.
Next, with thanks to SHINee's KEY, Kim Ki Bum,
the hospital director will say a few words.
- Yes. - The director?
The director will thank you with a speech?
(The hospital director's speech)
Thank you for visiting our hospital in person...
for your mother's retirement...
and showing us your warm sentiments.
- We are so grateful. - Goodness, no.
Actually, while I was talking to your mother,
I heard that she had been working...
at our hospital for 36 years and 8 months.
In fact, she has been working here for longer than I have.
As she worked here for so long and dedicated her youth,
I'm sure she has gone through hardships as well.
I was so grateful to her.
Especially, her son is carrying on her dedication...
and coming down here for the young patients...
- to encourage them. When I heard, - Right.
I wanted to express my gratitude.
- I think your mom is tearing up. - I know.
Thank you.
(His mom's last day at work shines even brighter.)
For my mom,
it must've been such a long period that also went by in a flash.
When she was working with children with cancer,
she was so sincere to them. She went through so much heartache.
I feel more relieved, actually.
We will be rooting you on. Thank you.
(Suddenly, they pass him a mic.)
Next, we will ask SHINee's KEY, Kim Ki Bum...
(What is it?)
Is it a congratulatory performance?
We will ask him to do a voice imitation.
For a speech with a big round of applause.
With a big round of applause.
You didn't think of this, did you?
Me? I just...
(Expectant)
(SHINee's KEY, Kim Ki Bum, you can do it!)
(The camera is ready.)
I have a loud voice, so...
(SHINee's KEY, Kim Ki Bum's donation speech)
Actually, my first donation was to this hospital,
and...
my dad said that I should donate some more money...
if I wanted to boost my mom's ego.
(Joking)
- That's right. - I tried to lighten the mood.
- Good job. - Nice.
I just wanted this money to be used for more people in need.
And I will also be rooting for...
everyone who will regain their health.
- Thank you. - Yes, thank you.
(Thank you.)
Next, we will have the donation delivery ceremony.
Have you not given it to them yet?
Please let him go home.
You should come up too. Let's take a picture.
Right, Mom. Come on up.
- You have to do this. - Yes, you do.
("SHINee's KEY, Donates 50,000 Dollars...")
("to Children's Hospital Patients")
This was almost as grand as an awards ceremony.
It's like you already went to the Entertainment Awards.
(By yourself)
With this, we will conclude today's ceremony.
- Goodness. - Thank you.
"Meeting adjourned."
Thank you.
- You look a lot like your mother. - Right?
Then, here...
(This isn't an easy thing to do.)
I was so drained. I look gaunt.
Every time I go to the hospital, my mom never forgets...
to take me to meet the young patients battling cancer.
Oh, to say hi.
So, we made rounds on two more floors and came back up.
Gosh, you did so well.
- We're back. - Hello.
- Hang on. I have to... - She's going home now, right?
- Yes. - Do you need to take this too?
My books and...
(It's time to clean out her beloved desk too.)
- All her things... - I have these too.
and the presents that she got.
Nurse Kim, have you signed everything that needs approval?
I have signed everything that I got today.
If I missed something, I'll do it once I get home.
Gosh, she's leaving for good now.
How would she feel to clear everything out?
Oh, goodness.
(The end of a great chapter of 36 years and 8 months)
My photo from when I received an award.
(Chuckling)
(Her regular daily life spent here...)
- Will you be okay? - Yes, I'll put it in like this.
The day for clearing out Mom's space has actually arrived.
That's what I kept thinking.
It was like when I graduated...
and cleared out my desk thinking,
"Am I really not coming back to this school?"
I can't even imagine what that feels like.
- Let's go. - Let's go.
- I'll be going now. - Bye.
Thank you for everything.
- Bye. - Bye.
I'll visit you at home later.
- Okay. - This feels so weird.
The last time riding the elevator.
(It's the last time riding the elevator she took every day.)
- Let's go. - Okay.
- Come on. - Let's go.
I'll drive.
- Will you drive? - Yes, give me the key.
(She's with her son on the last trip home from work.)
Let's go.
Go straight.
Yes, and move over to the first lane now.
She must've driven on this road so many times.
Goodness, now...
I won't be coming here very often anymore.
- She must be kind of sad. - Yes.
It doesn't feel real yet.
- I can't even imagine how it feels. - Right.
I mean, at the hospital, I have work to do.
So, it didn't feel real.
Even until today, I had work to do.
There wasn't much time to think about things.
Earlier at the hospital,
- things were so hectic that... - Right, at the hospital...
- it didn't even feel real. - Right.
- Yes. - I'm sure it didn't.
Goodness, I get to go home from work for the last time...
with my son.
It's so touching.
- It's weird. - I know.
You were so busy,
but you made time for me for a day at the end of the year.
I'm so grateful.
- Gosh, you did so well. - You really did.
- You must be a reliable son to her. - So nice.
How many people get to do this?
(She's even prouder that her son is driving for her.)
Before I started driving, Dad came to pick me up every day.
- That's amazing. - And he'd drop me off.
Was it 9 o'clock when we left?
I remember going there in the morning.
- Oh, really? - Yes.
- When we went to pick you up, - Yes?
I used to sleep in the car and stuff.
(The boy in the back seat has grown up in no time...)
(to drive his mom home now.)
When the sun sets like this, the drive home is so nice.
(Right then, the orange sky also congratulates her last trip home.)
Starting January 2,
what do I do if I don't go to work?
It feels like that in the morning.
- That's right. - When it's time to go to work.
These days,
I keep thinking about your grandma.
- Really? - Yes.
Your grandma was a strong woman, you know?
She was ahead of her time.
When I was growing up, your grandma...
Back then, people didn't send daughters...
- to college that often. - They didn't.
- It was like that back then. - Right.
But your grandma said she would support our education...
as long as we studied hard, regardless of gender.
That's amazing.
She said that even women had to work.
She said that a woman had to have financial independence...
to be able to have her own opinions and live her own life.
- She was a forward thinker. - Yes, she was.
- She was very progressive. - She really was.
My aunt became a doctor back then too.
I think that's so cool.
I'm just so grateful.
This was your first job.
- Gosh, she stayed at her 1st job. - For 36 years.
It's so impressive that our elders did that.
Because I was working,
I couldn't take care of you. Weren't you sad about anything?
Well, I just...
When I was little, I just thought all parents were like that.
That was my daily life.
When I got home, Grandma would be there.
I didn't know anything else.
I don't feel lonely about not having siblings either.
I've never had them, so I wouldn't know.
I've always been an only child.
(Her only son grew up bravely on his own.)
Until I turned ten years old,
I remember that Mom always worked in the emergency room.
I would always go in front of the ER...
and tell my mom...
that she did a great job today.
That was a big part of my life.
I've seen her since she worked a three-shift schedule.
Whenever she came home,
I remember Mom looking so tired.
Now that I look back,
she was married, raising a child,
and working the night shift.
- I learned what that meant later. - Gosh, that makes no sense.
- Just one of those would be hard. - It makes no sense.
We haven't done any of those things yet.
I've never seen her rest on both days of the weekend.
But with that day of rest, we'd go on family trips to Mount Jiri.
She'd work six days a week,
and on her one day off, she'd take her kid out to play.
It really makes no sense at all.
All I can say is that she's amazing.
If I were her, could I have endured it?
I sometimes think about that too.
Because it's been 36 years.
Every single day.
Maybe, she worked so sincerely...
because she wanted to be a better mom for me.
I think that could've been part of it.
I liked that I was there for the last part of her journey.
She must've been so happy.
(He's a reliable presence for his mom's last trip home.)
Let's go inside.
(They return home with their hands full of stuff.)
Oh, it's dark.
Gosh, let me go in first.
- Okay. - I have to go in first.
- What? - I have to go in first.
- I had set it up. - Oh, gosh.
(The surprise party that KEY had prepared since morning)
You were sweating buckets as you prepared it.
- You'll see it when it gets bright. - Yes.
- Ta-da! - What's this?
(She jumps up as if she didn't expect it.)
She jumped up.
What's this?
Why?
- Come on! - Oh, no!
- You didn't stick it on firmly. - I should've checked.
- The house must've been too hot. - It was really...
Oh, my. What is this?
(So touched)
Seriously, what is this?
(Flustered)
- Did you do this? - What is this? I didn't...
Darn it.
- Why? Did it fall off? - Hang on. Yes.
Darn it. What's this?
Darn it.
- Did you do this before you left? - Yes.
I set the whole thing up earlier.
No, but your mom liked it.
She looks so happy.
My mom just liked that.
- My goodness. - Here, look at this.
(Picking it up)
What is it?
(And he picks up...)
- Oh, my! - Goodness.
My gosh.
(A photo of his mom when she was younger)
(Surprised and touched, How did you prepare all this?)
Isn't it funny?
Goodness, what is this?
It was when I was in my third year at college,
for my white hat ceremony.
A white hat ceremony?
It's the day nursing students get their nurse's hats.
- These days, - It's like...
they call it the Nightingale Pledge.
- They look like fairies. - My gosh.
This must've been when Mom was in college.
(KEY was looking through old albums in the morning.)
The white hat ceremony.
(The white hat ceremony...)
I remembered that I had seen...
photos of my mom at her white hat ceremony.
The nurses... Oh, here it is.
- You took that out. - Yes.
At the end of this chapter in her life,
I wanted to congratulate her with the photo of her beginning.
I wanted to deliver a message that she did so well.
So, I wrote a letter on the back of the photo too.
- You're like an event planner. - That's so cool.
You did so well.
Goodness, what is this?
- Really? - Yes.
My son, come here.
All the children in this country hate this video.
Where else would I find a son like this?
Seriously, Ki Bum is the only one.
All the other children in the country will get cursed out.
Gosh, this is making me cry.
- Why are you crying again? - Oh, goodness.
It's not an easy thing for a son to do this for his mom.
Goodness, thank you.
- Start taking photos. - Photos?
I'll cook for you.
- Gosh, that's cool. - Little punk.
"I'll cook for you." My goodness.
That was so cool just now.
Your mom's group chat will be blowing up now.
Group chat.
My goodness.
(She's full of smiles at the thought of bragging about her son.)
She looks so happy.
(Grabbing)
- Is it okay I wrote on the photo? - Yes.
(She reads the sincere letter thoroughly as well.)
(To my incredible mom!)
I still have so many memories from when my mom...
worked in tougher conditions.
I can't believe that she's already retiring.
She worked really hard.
I think that's what I wanted to express on that photo.
That was the beginning.
I will treasure this for my whole life.
(I will treasure this for my whole life.)
Gosh, thank you.
Don't mention it. You can sit and wait.
Let me go and get changed.
(While his mom is changing, KEY gets dinner ready.)
There's no other son like you.
I feel so bad for my mom.
(He checks the food one last time too.)
Do you know what this is?
What is it?
This is Grandma's braised crab.
Really?
(Giggling)
Goodness, how did you think to make this?
I wanted to eat it.
- Really? - Yes.
Ki Bum, you know exactly what your mom would like.
Gosh, this is big. Look.
(A whole, plump crab)
- That looks so good. - We should eat one each.
- Goodness. - I should eat some crab too.
(Expectant)
Did you make this because you remembered...
- Grandma's braised crab? - Yes.
I wanted it so bad,
- but they don't sell it anywhere. - I know.
I figured out the recipe after several attempts.
I tried cooking it about three times before.
- Oh, really? - Yes.
Since you're good at cooking, you can recall those old memories.
- I'll enjoy the meal. - I'll enjoy the meal.
- It's hot. - How should I cut it?
- Take the back... - Yes?
and hold it. Then you flip this part over.
- This back part? - Yes. That's it.
(She opens it as KEY demonstrated.)
- Like this? - Yes, like that.
- Gosh, this is... - The crabs have eggs in them now.
- The soy sauce is all absorbed. - Yes.
Oh, my gosh.
What is all this?
I never even thought to make something like this.
I'm so curious. Will it taste the same?
It tasted similar to me, but it should taste like that to you.
Let me see if it's seasoned right first.
- How is it? Does it taste the same? - It tastes just like Grandma's.
- Really? - I want to try that.
(Delighted)
- Gosh. - I can't imagine how it tastes.
- It's something we've never tried. - Right.
(A new dish that makes you curious of how it tastes)
- I'll get some on the rice. - Right.
(Placing the seasoned innards and roe on top of the rice)
(Taking a bite of the rich taste of the crab)
It's good, isn't it?
(The son grabs it with his hand...)
(and tears off the meat.)
I've never thought about making this.
- Even when I wanted to eat this. - That's the face you make...
when it's a familiar taste.
It's so good. Even though I made it, it's good.
Teach me the recipe.
I'll try making it too.
I brought the seed soy sauce from home.
- You did? - I used that for the sauce.
You can have this with Dad when I'm not around.
I took out all of the ingredients.
Use just a little bit of them.
Take a picture of them and use a little bit of them.
I placed all of them together.
When you try just the soy sauce,
you have to go, "It's salty."
That way, it will taste good with the crab.
- As it gets into the meat. - Right.
- But this is so good. - It's good, isn't it?
I'm having this after 20 years.
- It must be the same for you. - Right.
There's no place that makes it like this.
(The braised crab in soy sauce has returned thanks to her son.)
- It must be really good. - Right.
My mom usually never eats with her hands.
She's really enjoying it.
(Entranced)
(Mom is really enjoying it.)
Aren't I eating too well?
- Gosh. - It's fascinating to see this.
- I've never imagined this. - Gosh.
It's so good.
Crabs are dangerous.
Cooking is fine,
but it's the rest that feels tiresome.
(Taking a bite after getting a big spoonful)
(Eating without stopping)
- I'm so curious. - I'm so curious...
about how it tastes.
It looks like braised chicken.
- It does look like jjimdak. - Right.
There's the braised chicken and crab stew these days.
- That dish is red. - Right.
Jjimdak is made just with soy sauce.
It's right in between those two dishes.
I added in some Cheongyang red peppers.
It's spicy...
- and sweet with the soy sauce. - Gosh, that must be great.
- Dad would really like this. - Right.
My dad came that night.
Really?
- She emptied a whole bowl. - She ate more than I did.
You're eating really well.
What's going on today?
My goodness. Ms. Kim Sun Hee emptied a whole bowl of rice.
(Clean)
- I have something to give you too. - What?
I have no reason to get anything.
Wait right there. I prepared something for you too.
- What? - What could it be?
What could it be?
(His mother brings out something from her room.)
- We must be quite similar. - What is it?
A letter?
- It's a letter. - What is it?
Is it a Christmas card from you?
It's so pretty!
We always give each other these things.
- Really? - Yes.
That's so nice.
It was so pretty.
(I wanted to get it for you as it was so pretty.)
(Along with the small handwritten letter...)
- This is separate. - Right.
(Gasping)
Money?
Gosh.
Why all of a sudden?
Every Christmas,
- Really? - you gave me money.
I should make my mom watch this part only.
Me too. Just this part.
- Just send this moment. - Right.
- This is the perfect moment. - Right.
I think this will cover up for everything I did.
I had this thought in the past.
I had to take care of my child as he was my child.
I had to take care of my parents as they were my parents.
"What about me?"
It's the same for you right now.
There are times when you want to be taken care of...
- from someone. - Of course.
I wanted to do that for you.
You went through so much throughout the year.
You did too.
What's wrong with your ear? Is it bleeding?
- No. I was sweating. - He felt hot.
What's the temperature inside the house?
- Gosh. - Is it a sauna?
Please stop my parents.
Do you know the feeling...
- of the house boiling? - I do.
- It's because you're a singer. - Right.
They're always worried that I would feel cold.
(Her mother wanted to keep him warm since the morning.)
Gosh.
It still feels unreal to me,
but I wanted to make it a grand party.
I didn't expect this at all.
(We root for the 2nd chapter of your shining life.)
My mom's life that I see...
seems to have a lot of interesting moments in her future.
There were things that she wasn't able to do...
because of me or the family.
I hope that she will do...
everything she wishes to now.
I really wish for her to live freely now.
"The way you worked..."
"really affected the way I worked."
She can study whatever she wants to study.
She can enjoy her hobbies and work out.
If there's something that she needs, I will definitely help out.
I think it's my duty to help her out well.
He's so reliable.
Thank you.
We should celebrate one more time when Dad comes.
We ate that together that night.
I'll stay the night and leave tomorrow.
Sure.
You can go after seeing your dad.
Sleeping over for two nights means you're the best son.
I would have ten sons if they were like Ki Bum.
(Walking Mom for Act 2 of Her Life)
(Home Alone)
After Kwak Do Gyu,
we have a new smart Rainbow Club member...
- waiting for us. - Great.
Hey!
- I Can Do It Alone Very Well! - I Can Do It Alone Very Well!
It's time for the second guest.
I heard that as soon as this person's teaser came out,
people got ready to shop for this person's items.
- Really? - I love those kind of people.
She has a lot of must-have items.
- Uhm Jung Hwa and Shin Ha Kyun. - Right.
She was a rookie actress that showed her great presence...
amongst these great seniors.
- Her acting was great. - That's something hard to do.
Welcome, Jo Aram!
(Jo Aram)
(Hello)
- Hello! - Hello!
(The rising star that lives a smart life alone)
(Home Alone)
(Hey! I Can Do It Alone Very Well)
(She got everyone's attention with her extraordinary charisma.)
(A talented rookie that suits any kind of role)
(Actress Jo Aram)
- Gosh, hello! - Hello.
- Welcome. - Gosh!
- Hello. - Welcome.
Hello, I'm Actress Jo Aram.
- It's great to meet you all. - Gosh.
(It's great to see you.)
- What year were you born in? - I was born in 2000.
She's a millennium baby.
Do you not know anyone here?
- I don't. - I heard that there was someone...
who really wanted to meet here.
- Who is it? - Who is it?
(Really?)
I really like Wilson.
What?
He was chosen quite a lot as someone...
- who the guests wanted to meet. - Right.
He was mentioned often.
(Kian84 was the celebrity of the new members.)
You must've been quite excited to get mentioned.
(It's time to get into Aram's life.)
(Decorating Daily Life One by One)
Where is this?
Are there crickets here?
That was your alarm?
- That was your alarm? - Yes.
- You can get up with the sound? - That's nice.
Yes. I like the sounds of nature.
I see.
(She puts her cuddle toy to the side.)
(She greets the morning with the sound of crickets.)
(She moisturizes herself with the face mist by her bed.)
- Do you have dry skin? - It's really dry.
(Wriggling)
(She fixes her sleep socks.)
- You sleep with sleep socks on. - Yes.
I've seen a few who wear sleep socks.
Hello.
I have lived alone for a year and three months.
I am Jo Aram.
(I am Jo Aram.)
The room is well-lit.
(She embraces the sun as soon as she gets up.)
(Flapping)
(She makes her bed right away.)
It has been around three months since I have moved to this place.
(Aram's new house)
The overall atmosphere of the house...
was made to be cozy...
and like a place of rest.
I tried my best to make it feel comfortable.
Check out her kitchen. Gosh.
It's so neat.
She's really diligent.
(Aram's taste can be seen here and there.)
As for the bedroom,
I'm someone who is serious about getting good sleep.
The importance of sleep is really big to me.
It really is important.
It was based on feng shui.
That fake wall was set up based on feng shui.
(Fake wall based on feng shui)
- What? - Why?
I heard that it's good not to see the door while sleeping.
- Really? - Yes.
Do you order that wall on purpose?
I brought it from my previous house.
As it didn't fit perfectly,
I had to cut it on my own.
Did things work out after setting up that wall?
Yes. Well, I get good sleep.
She's young, but she's interested in these things too.
(A fake wall that guarantees great sleep)
(She uses the space of the inside of the wall.)
(The outside is decorated with the things she likes.)
That's a postcard of my favorite movie.
(She decorated the wall...)
(by hanging up the things she likes on her own.)
(By the kitchen,)
(there's a curtain that she hung up on her own!)
A lot of people separate that area as well.
(If you open the door besides that area,)
(the utility room is filled with Aram's touch as well.)
- You put up those curtains too? - Yes.
I think it makes a big difference to have things covered.
- Right. - She likes having things covered.
I covered all of the cleaning items.
They must be covered. That's really pretty.
I like traveling.
The postcards or items I bought while traveling...
that reveal my taste...
- are around the house. - That's so cute.
(The items are filled with her taste.)
- That's for tissues? - Yes.
Gosh, that's so cute.
She must like rabbits.
It's a house where I can fully rest.
I can't believe everything is kept so white and neat.
(Rolling)
(Feeling shy)
Is that really your bare face?
- Yes. - That's your bare face?
Didn't you forget to wash up your makeup from last night?
- She really has great skin. - I'm so jealous.
That's the skin of a human being? Gosh.
(She keeps her sleep socks on even in the restroom.)
You didn't put on the slippers?
I didn't. Why didn't I put them on?
- You feel shy, right? - I feel really shy.
- Right. - I feel so embarrassed.
This is fun to watch.
Hold on.
- What's so fun to watch, Kian84? - What are you saying?
- It's fun to watch how she lives. - What's so fun to watch?
It's really fun to watch how someone else lives life.
We watched different people live their lives every week.
We watch how others live every week.
So this is why people watch Home Alone!
What on earth is he saying?
(Feeling refreshed)
(That really woke me up.)
(She applies the skin lotion before the moisture goes away.)
(She takes care of her skin as soon as she gets up.)
So there are people who actually do that.
I do that every day too.
- Right. - We have Ki Bum too.
(She's setting up a wall of moisture unlike anyone else.)
(She's done with her morning routine.)
(She rushes somewhere after taking care of her skin.)
What is that?
- It's a hygrometer. - I don't have a hygrometer.
It's to check if they have enough water?
Yes. It's red if they are dry.
It's green if they are moist.
It's blue if they are completely wet.
I usually give them water when around two leaves are dead.
That means they are really strong.
They're trying hard to survive.
She's actually using a hygrometer.
That's amazing.
(She takes the dry plants after checking with the hygrometer.)
- It's really convenient. - That's nice.
(She checks the temperature of the water meticulously.)
I can tell she's a really neat person.
You changed the shower head, right?
You're right.
(It's time to wake the plants up as well.)
(You guys have to get moisturized too.)
(All living creatures in the house have been moisturized.)
(She heads to one side of the living room.)
- There's a fish tank. - Yes.
They are my pet fish.
I have raised them for six years.
It has been that long since I have raised them.
Then you've raised them since you were in high school.
Yes.
- You were in high school... - Yes.
six years ago.
- I was still in my 40s 6 years ago. - Gosh!
- You're a goblin. - You're right.
- You're younger than I thought. - I'm Mooblin.
- Gosh. - The Gong Yoo of Home Alone.
(The Gong Yoo of Home Alone)
- The router. - The router.
I have nine fish.
Their names are...
Ketchup, Mustard,
(Ketchup)
(Mustard)
Nacho, Cheese, and Garlic.
These five have names.
They look so pretty.
They aren't seawater fish, right?
- They aren't. - They are Cichlids.
You're right!
They must be raised just amongst themselves.
- You're right. - They are very violent.
You're right!
He's into vivariums.
- Actually, - She must love cooking too.
I really enjoyed the episode with your lizards.
- Gosh! - Right.
- He loves animals. - Right.
This is the best episode I've seen in a while too.
(You're right.)
How did you end up liking fish?
Ever since I was young,
- I enjoyed going to aquariums. - Right.
As I couldn't go all the time,
I wanted to make myself my own aquarium in the house.
When I became a college student,
I got the most amount of money during Seollal.
- For making bows? - Right.
- With that money... - You used that money.
Yes. I went to the aquarium street in Dongdaemun...
and set that up.
You had that in your parent's house and you brought it with you?
Yes. I moved the whole tank to my house.
(Rushing)
(She opens up the curtain...)
(and grabs something.)
What is she up to? Cleaning?
(She heads to the fish tank after getting something.)
(Putting together)
What is that?
It's a cleaning tool.
- It's to suck in the water. - It's a siphon.
- A siphon? - Yes.
- To fill it with new water? - Yes.
(She puts the cleaning tools to the side.)
(Let's wash my hands before I clean the fish tank.)
Is it not done with gloves on?
Gloves can also be bad for the fish,
so it's best to use bare hands.
I wash my hands just with water.
You have to be careful with chemical substances.
Right.
(Wiping)
(She starts with the wall of the fish tank.)
Hold on.
(Wiping)
Gosh, it looks really clean.
I'm wiping off things like moss.
As it's by the window, it slightly becomes mossy.
The moss isn't bad for the fish,
but it can look dirty from the outside.
That is why I wipe it away with the sponge first.
(Getting rid of the moss with the sponge)
(Heave-ho)
(She bites onto her lips.)
That is a lot of work.
(Moving)
(She takes the next cleaning tool after getting rid of the moss.)
(Pressing)
- What is that? - The siphon.
(What is she doing?)
I use a siphon used for cleaning.
It's to suck up the waste on the ground.
The light waste gets sucked up with the water.
- What about the sand? - So that's cleaned too.
The sand goes back down.
- It goes back down as it's heavy. - That's fascinating.
There's a tool that does that?
(Fascinated)
It's referred to as the water breaks.
It literally means the water becomes dirty.
It becomes murky.
To avoid the water from breaking,
the tank has to be cleaned to a certain extent.
It can't be cleaned too much.
The bacteria must be living for the fish to live.
So that is how I clean the fish tank.
The fish will die if it's too clean.
Right.
- There has to be some poop. - Right.
(There has to be some poop.)
That is a fascinating world.
You poopers!
Gosh, what is that?
- That's so much poop! - They're so nice.
They only pooped in one place.
- They're all potty-trained. - Potty-trained?
- How did you make that happen? - How did you make that happen?
Those fish dig up the sand with their mouths...
or live inside those rocks.
The waste gets collected into the rocks that don't get chosen.
They use them as toilets.
- Right. - They're so smart.
They are certain about their own areas.
Right. They are known for that.
- They are so smart. - That's nice of them.
(Feeling proud)
(She is completely focused on cleaning the fish tank.)
(She carried on for a while.)
That's so much work. When will she get done?
But you enjoy doing that, right?
Yes. It clears me from my thoughts.
She has a great sense of responsibility.
(This should be enough!)
(She discards the fish waste she collected diligently.)
(Grabbing)
(Touching)
- What are you doing? - The temperature...
- Do you do it with your hand? - Yes, I check it with my hand.
I do it by hunch.
(After checking the temperature, she comes back with water.)
(Touching the water here and there)
(She checks the temperature of both tanks with her hands.)
What's that?
I need to do a water change.
The temperature needs to be similar.
I've cleaned the fish tanks for many years.
Back in the day, I needed a thermometer.
Now, I can measure the temperature by using my hands.
So I match the temperature that way.
(Her golden hands let her measure the temperature.)
I add the water with a gentle flow so that the fish don't get startled.
- That's how I clean the tanks. - What's that water?
That's tap water I collected a day before.
- You need to do it in advance. - It's water with chlorine remover.
That's right.
(I'm proud of my work.)
(After cleaning the fish tanks)
(Opening)
(What should I eat?)
You cook.
It's clean.
- I enjoy cooking. - There are many things.
- I know. You divided things up. - She divided things up.
- Yes. - She's skilled.
(Grabbing)
(She takes out side dishes from the fridge.)
(The frozen rice and soup go into the microwave.)
Are those side dishes from your parents?
I made them myself.
- Did you make those side dishes? - Yes, I make them myself.
I've seen many people make...
- their own main dishes, - Seriously.
but not side dishes.
Most people eat their main dishes with their moms' side dishes.
She's very skilled.
Seriously.
Since I live alone, ordering food always yields leftovers.
That's why I don't order food.
You feel guilty if you get a lot of leftovers.
That's right.
(She transfers the beef and radish soup.)
- You divide it into small portions. - Yes.
I make the soup,
divide it into small portions, and freeze it.
- It's neat. - She's good at living alone.
(Humming)
You need an eating partner.
What will she watch?
My goodness.
- Is that your eating partner? - My goodness.
- It's Home Alone. - It's my eating partner.
I'm on TV.
It's the marathon episode.
I see that you like me.
It's the Cheongju Marathon.
She likes Home Alone.
(Thank you for the food.)
(She breaks down an egg.)
It looks tasty.
(She takes a big bite.)
(Humming in approval)
(A home-cooked meal is the best.)
(Crunchy)
(Impressed)
(She drinks the soup from the bowl.)
(My goodness)
She isn't watching Kian84 run.
That isn't true. I'm watching.
- How strange. - Don't be like that.
She's listening to the sound as if it's a radio show.
That's how it is when you watch TV.
She's treating it like a radio show.
(She keeps her ears open and eats with her mouth.)
(It's a precious meal with the side dishes she made.)
(It was a good meal.)
(Rubbing)
(Cleaning)
(She cleans the table as soon as she finishes eating.)
(She does the dishes right away.)
(With a few wipes,)
(the plate becomes clean.)
- She's good at housekeeping. - I know.
Look how clean the sink is.
There are no water stains.
(She hangs the gloves on the designated hanger.)
(Pressing)
- Coffee. - Yes.
(A cup of coffee for myself who worked hard in the morning)
(She goes somewhere while alleviating her tiredness.)
It's the place I cherish the most after the bedroom.
It's straight out of an interior design magazine.
It has a bit of an atmosphere.
Both the table and desk are wood-toned for the vintage vibe.
And I collect things one at a time.
It's fun to decorate the house with them.
(There are even props from her favorite animated movies.)
- Those props have meanings. - Yes.
(Aram sits in front of the desk of her favorite place.)
(Grabbing)
- All right. - What's that?
(Let's see.)
I love to decorate the diary.
- Decorating the diary. - Yes.
- Decorating the diary. - I haven't seen it in a while.
- Chan Hyuk's mom. - That's right.
That's right. His mom was a total expert.
(Searching for happiness)
(The drawer Aram is rummaging...)
(is full of items for decorating the diary.)
(What did she take out?)
(Stickers?)
I've collected them a bit at a time since high school.
If I go to Jeju Island,
I need stickers that have the charms of Jeju Island.
There are many special days...
like the day the shoot ended.
So I began collecting stickers that matched the theme.
I call that a binder.
It became thick.
- Now, it's about to burst. - It's about to burst.
- That's right. - It's about to burst.
That binder is a cherished possession of mine.
- You collected so many stickers. - How do you do that?
Do you know where everything is?
Yes. I keep them by type.
I organize them that way.
(She'll decorate today's memories in a pretty way.)
(Travel diary)
A receipt?
I recently went on a solo trip to Jeju Island.
My baggage went above the weight limit.
I found that situation funny...
when I thought about it.
So I kept the receipt on purpose.
"I'll put this in the diary."
There's a story.
(She already pasted photos from her Jeju Island trip.)
(Which stickers suit the Jeju Island trip?)
(Holding the stickers she picked in one hand)
(Opening the drawer)
(Are those tweezers in her other hand?)
(She takes off a sticker with the tweezers.)
You need to do it with tweezers.
(She decorates the empty space next to the photo.)
I watch many ASMR videos.
Really? I do too.
(Let's see.)
(She puts hearts next to her photo while reminiscing about the past.)
Two hearts.
(Rummaging)
That's a correction tape.
It's a double-sided tape, but it works like a correction tape.
- It looks so convenient. - It's very convenient.
- I didn't know that it existed. - There are so many cool products.
(On the piece of paper she pasted)
She's serious about decorating the diary.
(Aram's golden hands move busily for a while.)
She has no reason to go out. She has so many things to do.
She didn't look at her phone once.
I find that fascinating too. She doesn't look at her phone.
I don't look at my phone often.
When I sit there, I decorate the diary for 3 to 4 hours.
I don't think about anything.
I don't eat.
When I was really into it, I once did it for 14 hours.
(I love to decorate the diary.)
When I'm home,
people can't reach me.
Doing things I want to do in my private space...
is so comforting and nice.
She doesn't notice the passing time.
(She fills the memories of traveling with her unique sentimentality.)
My goodness.
It doesn't look messy, right?
(Proud)
(She turns over to a new page.)
(Rustling)
- What? - This is the shot I'm used to.
(Welcome to Aram's ASMR.)
(Crumpling up)
She crumpled it up...
- for the vibe. - That's right.
(You know this humidity, feeling, and sound, right?)
I know.
- That's how it goes. - That's right.
There's a bit of madness to it.
- It draws you in. - It does draw me in.
(In complete silence,)
(she focuses on her hobby.)
How pretty.
My goodness.
Her handwriting is pretty.
(It was raining, but I visited an exhibition by chance.)
If you decorate the diary in an analog way,
you can reminisce about the past more deeply.
I want to revisit the memories more nicely,
so I decorate my diary with my own tastes.
That's a legendary diary decoration.
(Aram's records of her youth will be kept for a long time.)
(Opening)
(Aram is done showering after decorating the diary.)
Her skin is perfect.
(She walks over to the vanity after washing up.)
(There isn't a speck of dust.)
It's clean.
There are brands she likes.
That's right.
(Her vanity is clean.)
(Shall I dry my hair?)
(She dries the roots thoroughly.)
- Are you wearing makeup? - Yes.
- You don't need to wear makeup. - Seriously.
(She puts makeup on her lips as well.)
Is she going somewhere?
I think she'll go outside now.
(She styles her own hair.)
She's good at using it.
I always ruin my hair.
(Last time, Na Rae couldn't do it even after an hour.)
I totally ruined it last time.
(Aram does it in 10 minutes.)
Is it the same device?
It's the same device.
(Aram comes out in her outside clothes.)
(I should go out now.)
Since she put on some makeup, She isn't going to a mart.
Where will she go to?
Maybe she'll go and buy fish food.
(Humming)
- Many people use wired earphones. - Yes.
Are wired earphones in vogue these days?
They evoke sentimentality.
Okay.
(She arrives at a place with cheerful steps.)
(A bus stop)
If she's taking a bus,
it must be someplace far.
Is she going to an academy?
(While she ties her hair,)
(the bus sets off with Aram inside.)
I rarely leave the house unless I have a schedule.
But I can't give up on that place.
It's a place that makes a homebody leave the house.
It's a place I absolutely cherish.
This stop is the Seoul Hang Love Hospital.
(This is my stop.)
(Getting up)
(When she arrives at her favorite place,)
(the sky is already dark.)
Where is she?
- I don't recognize the place. - No.
Is she in Gangnam?
(Walking over)
It looks like an academy.
Maybe she boxes.
What is this place?
(Excited)
It looks like a cafe.
An exhibition?
Hello.
(Her jaw drops.)
(My goodness)
(Cute stationery items)
They're for decorating the diary.
How pretty.
- The shop sells all of them. - Yes.
There's a variety.
It's like a boutique for people who like clothes.
That's right.
(The stationery store is full of cute items.)
I absolutely love small and precious things.
It's a place that has all of such items,
so I visit 2 or 3 times a month.
My goodness.
Looking around is a therapeutic experience.
(Her heart flutters.)
(They're so pretty.)
- You like cute things. - Yes.
Even when I don't buy things, I go to look.
(Her heart flutters.)
How cute.
That voice means she wants to buy it.
It's cute indeed.
(Grabbing)
It's so pretty.
Will you buy more?
(She has many items for diary decoration at home.)
(But each diary decoration item is unique under the sky.)
(I must buy it.)
(Gosh, what's this?)
- What's that? - What's that?
How do I use it?
- Is it a masking tape cutter? - That's right.
- I see. - Instead of scissors...
So that you can carry it around more easily,
it's shaped like tweezers.
There's a blade inside.
- I didn't know such items existed. - You can carry it around.
It's convenient and clean.
I'll use it well.
(I have scissors, but I need a clean tape cutter.)
I'll have one in mint.
(She justifies her purchase.)
I'll buy these items.
There are so many pretty items.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
(The homebody's next destination)
- Another shop? - What? Is it another shop?
Hello.
(It's a shop that has a different vibe.)
- This shop is bigger. - There'll be many cute items.
(There are household items...)
(as well as cute props.)
(Glancing over)
How cute.
What is it?
She can't come back to her senses.
I'd go crazy about them.
(What should I do? It's so cute.)
(My goodness)
It's so cute.
- Magnets? - Those are magnets.
They're a bit cute.
They're cute.
What? It's nice.
It's nice.
- How pretty. - Isn't it cute?
Please pack these items.
(She purchases them without hesitation.)
(Happy)
Sell a lot. Thank you.
(She walks out with satisfied steps.)
(My goodness)
Control yourself.
Oh, no.
She's Bankruptcyping.
What's this?
What are you?
- What are those? - What are those?
(What are those?)
(Rocks with eyes?)
They were the cutest.
- Aren't they really cute? - They're really cute.
- What are those? - They're really cute, right?
They're pet rocks.
- Pet rocks. - What? Rocks?
- Rocks. They're pet rocks. - So...
they aren't even amethysts.
Our dads collected viewing stones.
- That's different. - That's basically the same thing.
Yes, that's the same thing.
- Those are pet rocks too. - Yes.
There isn't much meaning.
(They're both rocks in the end.)
(Staring)
(They aren't just rocks.)
- Pet rocks? - Tear stains.
They shed tears later.
What?
I find them fascinating.
- They're ten dollars each. - Ten dollars?
- My goodness. - If their eyes change...
- Right? They're worth the money. - I know.
Which one should I get?
Aren't there bigger ones?
(Her heart flutters.)
(My goodness)
(She almost gets a heart attack.)
(Lethal)
- My goodness. - Isn't it so cute?
It's like a baby.
Isn't it so cute?
The world is going insane.
What?
(A culture shock)
I won't be able to copy that.
Gosh, that's...
Seriously.
I was okay with rocks, but the hat...
The hat gave me a pause.
Aram, you should earn money very diligently.
- You should work endlessly. - You should work endlessly.
- Pet rocks. - You spend money extravagantly.
You spend a lot of money.
(She touches the pet rock that makes her spend money.)
Okay. I choose you.
She likes cute things.
That was why she wanted to see Wilson.
This one? That one?
- It needs a house. - It has a house.
It's a set.
It's cute.
It's so cute.
(What?)
"The day you name it is the rock's birthday."
(The day you name it is the rock's birthday!)
You put a beanie on a rock.
You buy it a house.
- Who does that? - It even has a birthday.
- My goodness. - What's that?
- Birthday? - People do all sorts of things.
A rock's first birthday party.
Will you be the host at the rock's first birthday party?
"Dear guests."
(The first birthday party of a rock in Korea)
(My rock turned one after crying.)
(We'll look forward to seeing the doljabi.)
It's your birthday today.
(Eat my sadness and grow up.)
"Eat my sadness and grow up."
My heart aches.
- It's ten dollars. - Okay.
(Crying)
You must've spent a lot of money.
I can't believe that you purchased a rock.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
(It was a satisfying shopping trip.)
(Humming)
This will be Wilson's friend.
(She comes back home with the stone whose birthday is today.)
I'm back.
(Flicking)
(She goes to the kitchen after changing.)
(Thinking)
All right.
(Let me see.)
(Her fridge is neatly organized.)
(The vegetables are prepped and portioned.)
She has a lot of stuff in the fridge.
(As she takes them out one at a time,)
(she already has this much food outside.)
(First, she grabs the pot.)
(Pouring water)
(Placing)
She's using two burners.
- Gosh, she's using both burners. - Right.
When I had breakfast today,
I finished all the side dishes.
I need to make a new batch of side dishes...
and store them in the fridge.
I made the side dishes I usually eat.
People don't make side dishes these days.
- They don't. - People rarely make...
- side dishes. - They usually cook main dishes.
Actually, side dishes...
- They're not hard to make. - Right.
But once you start cooking them,
- they require a lot of effort. - Right.
- They're time-consuming too. - They are.
- And you end up having leftovers. - Yes.
(But this girl who was born in 2000 makes side dishes for herself.)
Quail eggs.
(She rinses the quail eggs with water.)
(Eating one)
Dark soy sauce.
(She opens up the cabinet while looking for soy sauce.)
(They're neatly organized, so it's easy to find them.)
Oh, my.
- She's so organized. - Yes.
(Neatly organized, so they're easy to find)
Soy sauce.
(I found the soy sauce.)
So you rarely get food delivered to your house, right?
Right. I rarely do.
(She grabs a potato next.)
(Slicing)
(The potatoes are nicely julienned.)
(Adding the quail eggs into the boiling base broth)
(While waiting for them to be braised,)
(she prepares the next side dish.)
(Julienned potatoes)
- Gosh. - That looks so good.
(Stir-frying them with both of her hands)
(The finishing touch)
- That's a great side dish. - The julienned potatoes?
- They're tasty. - Stir-fried julienned potatoes.
- They're tasty. - Yes.
(Let me taste it.)
(Humming in approval)
I think there's a certain sense of happiness cooking brings.
It's an act I do for myself.
It feels like I'm giving a present to myself.
So I do think I tend to like cooking.
Since I have to work,
I can't cook every day.
That's why to prepare for those days,
when I cook side dishes, I cook a lot.
(I'm so busy.)
That's so amazing.
(Getting a new pan ready)
(Green onions)
(Fishcakes)
Gosh, you're stir-frying fishcakes too.
That looks tasty.
I don't think anyone I know...
- makes side dishes at home. - Same here.
(Having a bite of this too)
(Humming with satisfaction)
I like that her side dishes aren't pretentious.
- You know... - Gosh, you and pretenses.
- What are pretentious side dishes? - You know...
people say they make French food or other international dishes.
Why is French food pretentious?
Some people make international side dishes.
- To look cool. - He's sitting next to you.
- Well... - That's me.
- What was that? - Why not international side dishes?
- They're completely fine. - So...
A certified Western-cuisine cook is sitting next to you.
- Right. - This one was imported too.
- You love imported goods the most. - Well...
- Your watch is imported too. - He loves foreign luxury goods.
- Fine. - He's a fan of Western items.
Moms would make those side dishes.
(She cooks the next dish without a break.)
What's that?
- She's adding them. - Apples and rice?
Apples and rice?
- What's that? - What is that?
(She adds a splash of soy sauce...)
(and salted shrimps to season the food.)
What's she doing?
(Smelling)
(Pouring it to the chopped chives)
I'm going to make chive kimchi.
- You'll make kimchi? - Kimchi?
- You'll make kimchi on a whim. - Yes.
- You also make kimchi? - Yes.
- I mean... - That's how you make kimchi.
- Yes. - She makes it like fresh kimchi.
- No way. - I like kimchi.
- You don't buy kimchi then. - No.
- Gosh. - I make them at home.
(Squeezing out minced garlic)
(Adding onions and carrots generously)
(The secret ingredient of chive kimchi is the sesame oil.)
(The girl born in 2000 makes chive kimchi at home.)
She really cooks for herself properly.
- She really does. - Gosh, that looks good.
Fresh kimchi is so tasty.
(Let me check the seasoning.)
(It passes.)
Good.
- How can she do that for herself? - She's good.
When I buy groceries, I have leftover food.
I end up cooking because I don't want to waste...
- the leftover ingredients. - Right.
- That's true. - Yes.
(She grabs the paper towel after transferring the side dishes.)
(She wipes the edges of the containers.)
Gosh, that too? She's super neat. She's great in the kitchen.
My mother does that.
- That keeps things clean. - Yes.
(She sprinkles sesame seeds to the chive kimchi too.)
(I'm done making the chive kimchi too.)
(She makes 4 side dishes in no time.)
- Gosh. What... - She's so neat.
(Pounding)
Someone is here.
Garlic?
I don't think that's garlic.
(Giggling)
What's that?
- Deodeok? - It's deodeok?
(The cutting board is covered with deodeok.)
You're pounding on the deodeok?
- Yes. To make grilled deodeok. - The grilled deodeok is tasty.
Do you run a restaurant?
Do you run a side dish store?
Your side dish store would do well.
Right.
(Rolling on the deodeok to flatten it more)
This is relieving my stress.
No one born in 2000 would make grilled deodeok in their spare time.
Right. That's...
I've never seen this white precooked deodeok.
(Humming)
(She's joyfully pounding on it as if she's doing laundry.)
All done.
The girl born in 2000 is spreading out the deodeok.
(Coating)
- Gosh. - What are you coating them with?
For the first layer, I coat them with soy sauce.
I grill them first.
And then I coat them with a red sauce and grill them.
So you grill them two times?
- Right. - My goodness.
(Adding the sauces as if she has done it many times before)
(She makes the second-layer sauce in no time.)
(Cooking the soy-sauced-up deodeok)
- I see. You cook them first. - Yes.
- Is that a necessary step? - Yes.
- Right. - That way, it's tastier.
(Coating them with the red sauce)
This is amazing. How could she think to make this at home?
Totally.
(Flipping)
(She skillfully flips over the deodeok.)
(Shaking)
(She finishes the grilled deodeok with sesame seeds too.)
(Humming)
How can she cook so neatly? She didn't spill anything.
My gosh. Look.
- Goodness. - They look like store-bought.
(Stir-fried fishcakes, stir-fried potatoes,)
(chive kimchi, jangjorim, grilled deodeok)
(She will finish the side dishes instead of having delivery food.)
She doesn't eat delivery food.
Then she eats slowly.
She smiles at a stone.
- She'll live out her life well. - Yes.
(She grabs the wet wipe for the kitchen.)
(She starts cleaning right after cooking.)
Her induction range is that clean?
Look at the induction range shining even when she cooks a lot.
I see no oil stains either.
(She can't allow even a single stain.)
(She wipes the wall too.)
Nothing got on the white counter top.
No way.
It's not easy to maintain the white counter top that clean.
(Opening up)
(She grabs something rustling.)
- She's so frugal. - She's frugal.
(She reuses the plastic bags as the food waste bags.)
Gosh, she's amazing.
Out of all the people born in 2000...
I've never met anyone who manages her house better than her.
(Smiling)
(I cleaned everything to perfection.)
All right.
Gosh, she really knows her stuff.
She puts the plastic sheet over the container.
- Right. - To store them longer.
- Right. - That way, it doesn't smell.
(She puts the container in the fridge right away.)
(I won't have to worry about side dishes for a while.)
(Grabbing)
- The items you bought today? - Yes.
- The stone. - Take the stone out.
- You must take the stone out. - The stone feels stuffy inside.
(Laughing)
It's the stone.
It's in the plastic bag. It can't breathe then.
(She carefully takes out the rest of the items.)
I'm very happy with it.
(Raising)
What's that?
I told you about it. The zoomers take aerial shots.
- It will be in the diary. - Yes.
It will be in it later.
(She loves it.)
Even if I don't do anything special, it brings me joy.
Since I live alone,
I'm in the process of finding out about myself more.
I learned that I like plants, fish, and cooking food.
I clearly know what I like.
That brings up my self-esteem too.
It feels like I'm giving myself a joyful day every day.
That's how I feel most of the time.
I think I can treasure myself a little more.
I can do a good job.
(Placing her pet stone in the plant pot)
- I put it there. - That's so cute.
- That's cute. - Put it in the house.
What about its house?
Hold on. Those stones aren't your pet stones?
They don't come from a good family.
- She cherishes her everyday life. - Right.
She's amazing.
(Next story)
(CODE KUNST is shopping...)
(with someone.)
(It's his younger brother who looks just like him.)
(I prepared something for you.)
(Heart-pounding)
(For his brother who will get married soon,)
(he wants to buy his brother shoes for the wedding.)
(He already knows what his brother likes.)
(You're the best.)
(I don't want to go down the stairs.)
(He's the cool brother only for a moment.)
(He goes back to the playful brother.)
(Spending time together makes them nostalgic.)
(Nostalgic about their bets)
(You're making my blood hot now.)
(The dribbling is extraordinary for Sakuragi KUNST.)
(His brother is getting competitive too.)
(Eat your poop.)
(In the end, they play dirty like immature kids.)
(They become boys when they're together.)
(From Men to Boys with His Forever Best Friend)
(Jang Woo is standing in front of the frozen valley.)
(Sniffling)
(Grunting)
(It's been a long time.)
(To absorb the energy of Mother Nature,)
(I'm going camping.)
(Let's awaken my spirit in Mother Nature for the new year.)
(He decided to dive into the water.)
(Screaming)
(Spirit of the valley,)
(come to me.)
(Passed out)
(It's cold.)
(I'm hungry.)
(Just like a 1st-generation camper,)
(he uses three braziers.)
(Let me fill my stomach with good energy too.)
(Spirit of the New Year, Flame Up)